Yang, Bo

Developer



+1-415-420-9693



https://yang-bo.com



pop.atry@gmail.com



pop_atry



yang_bo



955091



Atry

About me -

I am a developer who knows how to create application frameworks.

I founded various open-source projects for creating micro-services. neural networks, reactive GUIs, and DSLs, which are stared 3000+ times on Github.

My current interesting is machine learning engineering or development in functional programming languages, especially for creating developer tools or frameworks.

Skills

Scala

Machine Learning

Software Design

Agile Project Management

Hack ★5.5 Haxe ★5.5 OpenCL ★5 DevOps *5 ActionScript *4 C++ *4 Java *4 JavaScript *4 Rust *4 OCaml *4 Testing *3 C *3 Spark *3 Akka *3

(*)[The skill scale is from 0 (Fundamental Awareness) to 6 (Expert).]

Open-source projects

2021-2022 HHVM C++/Rust/OCaml

is Meta's virtual machine running Hack. I ported the open source branch of HHVM to

Nix and created CI pipeline for building, testing, and packaging HHVM.

2018-present Dsl.scala

is a framework to extend Scala language features in libraries. I also ported this frame-

work to Haskell as Control.Dsl.

2016-present Deep Learning. scala and Compute. scala

are libraries for creating complex neural networks.

2015-present Binding.scala

Scala

Scala

is a reactive templating language for creating web and desktop GUI.

2015-2016 Microbuilder Haxe / Scala / Java / JavaScript

is a toolkit that helps you build system across micro-services implemented in various

languages communicating via RESTful JSON API.

2012-presenthaxe-continuation

Haxe

provides ${\tt async/await}$ syntax for Haxe.

2010-present protoc-gen-as3

ActionScript3

is a Protocol Buffers plugin for ActionScript 3.

2007-presentother 100+ of open-source projects

Publications

2017 DeepLearning.scala 2.0: Statically Typed Neural Networks

2017 More than React

Adobe Flex 3: Training from the Source (translator) 2009

2017	Deeplearning.Scala——Thoughts and practice	s on open source deep
	learning framework	DBTC
2017	Monadic Deep Learning	Strange Loop
2017	Neural Networks & Functional Programming	ArchData Summit · Beijing

2016 More than Async QCon · Beijing 2015 Specific-domain extension in an universal language **ECUG Con**

Experience

2019-2022 Meta Platforms Inc Software Developer

> I built machine learning infrastructure to detect fraud in payments and integrate it into various products. Then I moved to Hack/HHVM OSS team, maintaining HHVM's open

source branch.

2015-2019 Thoughtworks Inc

Senior Consultant / Lead Consultant

I maintained some open-source projects sponsored by ThoughtWorks. I also took the role of consultant or technical leader in various delivery teams for creating mobile and

web applications and data platforms.

2014 Shenzhen QiFun Network Corp., LTD

I led the Q-Force Team in developing game engine along with its related tools, and two

mobile games.

2011-2013 Shenzhen Putaoteng Network Technology Co., Ltd.

Co-founder

Chief Programmer

I led the start-up team in developing a 3D side-scrolling game engine VinyHome and a social game Nan Da Nu Pei.

2008-2011 NetEase, Inc.

Chief Programmer

I participated in various product teams as a developer or the technical lead, including Zhan Guo Feng Yun (web game), Ka Pai Dui Jue (web game), Deepcold (3D game

2007 Beijing HiPiHi Information Technology Corp.,Ltd

Software Engineer

I developed variant components of both client-side and server-side for a 3D virtual

world, HiPiHi World.

2006-2007 Beijing AutoNavi Software Co., Ltd. Software Engineer

As a developer, I developed some components for a 3D navigation software.

Education

2002-2006 Southwest University of Political Science and Law

Bachelor Of Laws